{
    "id": "7977970be2914dbc8a48b8fc3ccddc81",
    "title": "So That, For, To | Expressing Purpose",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I talked to the shy girl ................................ that she would not feel left out.",
            "description": "We use the pattern so that to express the purpose here.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "for",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We stopped at the restaurant .............................. lunch.",
            "description": "Before a noun 'for' indicates the purpose in doing something.",
            "answers": [
                "so that",
                "to",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We stopped at the restaurant .................................... lunch.",
            "description": "For cannot be used before a verb in this sense.",
            "answers": [
                "for having",
                "to have",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I went to America ................................. my brother.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "for seeing",
                "to see",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A barometer is used ................................. pressure.",
            "description": "For + ing can be used to express the purpose of a thing when that thing is the subject of the clause.",
            "answers": [
                "to measure",
                "for measuring"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He went to London .................................. for work.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "for looking",
                "to look"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I warned him ................................... he would not repeat the same mistake.",
            "description": "Before a clause we use so that.",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "to",
                "so that"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We eat .................................. live.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "for",
                "so that"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We eat .................................. we may live.",
            "description": "We use so that before a clause to express purpose.",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "to",
                "so that"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We started early ................................... we would not be late.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "to",
                "so that"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We bought some burgers ................................ eat on the way.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "so that",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He was sent to prison ................................... stealing.",
            "description": "For + ing form can be used to explain the behaviour that caused the reaction mentioned in the previous part of the sentence.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "so that",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}